<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-07T22:29:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Whisky Time Show</title><subtitle>Two regular guys drink and review whisky.</subtitle><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><entry><title type="html">Yamazaki Mizunara 18 Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/08/07/Yamazaki-Mizunara-18.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yamazaki Mizunara 18 Review" /><published>2018-08-07T13:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-07T13:08:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/08/07/Yamazaki-Mizunara-18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/08/07/Yamazaki-Mizunara-18.html">&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/785NfDu23p8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we try our most expensive whisky ever on the Whisky Time Show: the mythical Yamazaki Mizunara 18. Will it live up to the crazy price and expectations? Watch now to find out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bruichladdich Octomore 8.1 and 8.3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/05/30/Bruichladdich-Octomore.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bruichladdich Octomore 8.1 and 8.3" /><published>2018-05-30T13:08:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T13:08:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/05/30/Bruichladdich-Octomore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/05/30/Bruichladdich-Octomore.html">&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IFRiwJ-XIrk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing better than Octomore is more Octomore! We've got a bunch of bottles of the Bruichladdich's 8th edition of Octomore, and we're gonna try the 8.1 and 8.3. Which one do we like better? Watch now to find out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elijah Craig Small Batch Barrel Proof &amp;amp; Colonel E.H. Taylor Small Batch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/02/28/Elijah-Craig-Colonel-E-H-Taylor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elijah Craig Small Batch Barrel Proof &amp; Colonel E.H. Taylor Small Batch" /><published>2018-02-28T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-28T12:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/02/28/Elijah-Craig-Colonel-E-H-Taylor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/02/28/Elijah-Craig-Colonel-E-H-Taylor.html">&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TmTxOtkq0R4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devin doesn't usually drink Bourbon, so I had him try two very good bourbons: Elijah Craig Small Batch Barrel Proof C17 and Colonel E.H. Taylor Small Batch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Colonel E.H. Taylor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This my benchmark for good bourbon. It smells like a good bourbon, and tastes like you would expect a good bourbon to taste. It's bright, fruity, and a little sweet with good multidimensional flavors and very easy to like. I brought it to a family Thanksgiving dinner and everyone loved it. We would recommend not adding any water because it's already so great straight out of the bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Elijah Craig Small Batch Barrel Proof C17&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is a little more complicated. At 131 proof, we found it a bit harsh when drinking it neat. However, after adding water, it lost a bit of flavor. It seems to be very difficult to add the correct amount of water to this one, so it just becomes too much of a chore to drink. Given that the price is now inflated from the Whisky Advocate whisky of the year award, we recommend the Colonel E.H. Taylor small batch over the Elijah Craig, at least until the price for the Eljah Craig comes back down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nikka Whisky Single Malt Yoichi</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/02/06/Nikka-Single-Malt-Yoichi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nikka Whisky Single Malt Yoichi" /><published>2018-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-06T12:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/02/06/Nikka-Single-Malt-Yoichi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/02/06/Nikka-Single-Malt-Yoichi.html">&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DEcDjFzkBW4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friend just returned from Japan with a fancy bottle of Nikka Whisky Single Malt Yoichi so we had to stop by for an impromptu Whisky Time Show shot and edited on my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Single Malt Yoichi has a bit of a darker character with a little bit of chocolate and a hint of smoke. Supposedly it has a touch of fruit in there as well but I wasn't tasting it that day. I will have to try it again to see if I can find the fruits somewhere. Overall not too bad, but also didn't blow me away. Can't complain when it's free though so big thanks to our friend Takusan for sharing this Nikka whisky with us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glenfiddich Winter Storm, Glenfarclas 25, Glenmorangie Nectar D’Or</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/01/31/Glenfiddich-Winter-Storm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glenfiddich Winter Storm, Glenfarclas 25, Glenmorangie Nectar D'Or" /><published>2018-01-31T12:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-31T12:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/01/31/Glenfiddich-Winter-Storm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/01/31/Glenfiddich-Winter-Storm.html">&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oaMaJYJX9Yk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I make Devin blind taste Glenfiddich Winter Storm, Glenfarclas 25, and our old favorite, Glenmorangie Nectar D'Or. Does the high profile Glenfiddich Winter Storm live up to its high price and exlusivity? Does the Nectar D'Or hold its own against two higher price whiskies? Watch our long video filled with dramatic tasting pauses to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Glenfiddich Winter Storm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devin's verdict: Very fruity and confusing. Hints of wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke's verdict: It has the complexity and depth of a 21 Glenfiddich with an extra layer of sweet, fruity ice wine taste. It's good but very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've tried everything else and need something new, try to track down a bottle of this if you can. If you have a limited budget, get a bottle of Nectar D'Or and Glenfarclas 25 for about the same price as one bottle of Winter Storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Glenfarclas 25&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devin's verdict: the heaviest of the three in terms of flavor and alcohol kick. Good options for when you're feeling like a more intense whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke's verdict: Very full oaky, dark, flavor with great influences from the oak it's been sitting in for 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update from Luke: After trying this a few more times, I don't like it. I think 25 years might be too long for this one. It's very bland, there's not much flavor, just oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Glenmorangie Nectar D'Or&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still one of our favorites. It's a little lighter and less intense than the other two but that makes it a great every day, go to whisky.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lagavulin Feis Ile 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/01/24/Lagavulin-Feis-Ile-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lagavulin Feis Ile 2017" /><published>2018-01-24T20:32:56-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-24T20:32:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/01/24/Lagavulin-Feis-Ile-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2018/01/24/Lagavulin-Feis-Ile-2017.html">&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oaMaJYJX9Yk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reflect on 2017 with a bottle of Lagavulin Feis Ile 2017. This particular Lagavulin was Luke's favorite whisky of 2017. Devin's favorite was the Bruichladdich Octomore 7.3, but we unfortunately did not have that on hand for this video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lagavulin Feis Ile 2017 is double matured in moscatel casks and it is phenominal. It's thick and oily but also well balanced. The moscatel casks give it just a hint of sweetness that nicely complements the peaty smokiness.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro to Islay: Laphroaig 10 &amp;amp; Ardbeg 10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/12/03/ardbeg-10-laphroaig-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to Islay: Laphroaig 10 &amp; Ardbeg 10" /><published>2017-12-03T20:32:56-08:00</published><updated>2017-12-03T20:32:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/12/03/ardbeg-10-laphroaig-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/12/03/ardbeg-10-laphroaig-10.html">&lt;p&gt;Ardbeg 10, Laphroaig 10, two popular entry level Islay whiskies, which one do we prefer? Since Devin is still lost in Europe, Luke makes the decision alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VzzgvUWWtO0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ardbeg 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke: Not a fan. The nose is great but it has a very strange chemical taste that is not pleasant. It's too astringent and brings to mind ethanol and cleaning supplies. Maybe this is a bad batch or maybe it's just not my style, but something is off with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Laphroaig 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke: Laphroaig Quarter Cask is one of my favorites, and while this is no quarter cask, it's much more drinkable than the Ardbeg. Very pleasant smokiness with hints of coffee and spice. If you try real hard, you can imagine this is as good as the quarter cask, but if you drink them side by side, the 10 is clearly not as sophisticated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to save money, go for the Laphroaig 10. It costs lest and is more approachable. Try the Ardbeg 10 at a bar or at a friends before you invest in a bottle because it is unique. If you have the money, skip both of these and upgrade to Laphroaig Quarter Cask or Ardbeg Uigeadail because they are much better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html">Ardbeg 10, Laphroaig 10, two popular entry level Islay whiskies, which one do we prefer? Since Devin is still lost in Europe, Luke makes the decision alone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glenmorangie Nectar D’Or &amp;amp; G&amp;amp;M Mortlach 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/05/20/glenmorangie-mortlach.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glenmorangie Nectar D'Or &amp; G&amp;M Mortlach 15" /><published>2017-05-20T21:32:56-07:00</published><updated>2017-05-20T21:32:56-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/05/20/glenmorangie-mortlach</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/05/20/glenmorangie-mortlach.html">&lt;p&gt;Glenmorangie Nectar D'Or and Gordon &amp; MacPhail's Mortlach 15 year are two excellent sub $100 whiskies. They are very different, but we'll compare them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IRCneeGy3Qw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nectar D'Or&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glenmorangie's Nectar D'Or is one of our favorite whiskies. It's available at a great price, and it's finish in sauternes casks gives it a fruity and slightly sweet taste. It's not an overpowering sweetness, just a hint of honey. If you have a sweet tooth, you'll probably love this whisky. Even if you don't have a sweet tooth, you probably still like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Mortlach 15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gordon &amp; MacPhail Mortlach 15 is a classic sherry cask whisky. It's aged in first fill and refill sherry casks, and has a full palate with hints of raisins. We really enjoyed this one, it's a great benchmark for quality sherried whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these are great, and there's no clear winner or loser here. If you are looking for something a little more sweet, try the Nectar D'Or. If you want to try a classic Speyside sherry cask whisky, go for the Mortlach. You can't go wrong adding one or both to your collection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html">Glenmorangie Nectar D'Or and Gordon &amp; MacPhail's Mortlach 15 year are two excellent sub $100 whiskies. They are very different, but we'll compare them anyway.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glenfiddich 12 &amp;amp; the Macallan 12</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/03/29/glenfiddich-12-macallan-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glenfiddich 12 &amp; the Macallan 12" /><published>2017-03-29T21:32:56-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-29T21:32:56-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/03/29/glenfiddich-12-macallan-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2017/03/29/glenfiddich-12-macallan-12.html">&lt;p&gt;When we first started drinking whisky many years ago, we did a blind tasting of all the whisky that we had to see what we liked best. Luke's favorite was the Glenfiddich 12 and Devin's was the Macallan 12. Today we take a journey back in time and revisit these two historic whiskies from our past. Whether you are just getting started on your whisky journey or looking for an affordable, quality whisky, Glenfiddich 12 and Macallan 12 are two great options for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HuzeJw_Velg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Glenfiddich 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glenfiddich is a private, family owned distillery. They have 28 stills and sell over a million cases a year, and that's because it's good stuff. The 12 year is very affordable and Luke used to prefer it to the 15 or 18 year. The taste is light and fruity, slightly sweet, a hint of oak, and very approachable for new scotch whisky drinkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Macallan 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Macallan 12 is great because The is part of the name. They are another big whisky producer and owned by the Edrington Group. The Macallan 12 is a little bit more expensive, but it is a little bit fuller bodied than the Glenfiddich 12. You get a lot more flavors and complexity in this one, a little vanilla, a little sweet and spicy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After revisiting these two old favorites, we think the Macallan 12 is the slightly better whisky, which might be why it costs a little bit more. The Glenfiddich is still good, but when compared to the Macallan, it's got a little bit less going on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Luke &amp; Devin</name></author><summary type="html">When we first started drinking whisky many years ago, we did a blind tasting of all the whisky that we had to see what we liked best. Luke's favorite was the Glenfiddich 12 and Devin's was the Macallan 12. Today we take a journey back in time and revisit these two historic whiskies from our past. Whether you are just getting started on your whisky journey or looking for an affordable, quality whisky, Glenfiddich 12 and Macallan 12 are two great options for you.</summary></entry></feed>